[barking growl]
Excuse me,
white, blue and pink
is where it's at.
End of conversation.
It's a good look,
I'm not saying
it's not a good look.
Mine's just cooler.
That's subjective.
Exactly.
My Gi color
is subjectively
cooler than yours.
Do you even know
what "subjective" means--
Will you two knock it off?
Of course, Lloyd.
Right after you confirm my Gi
is the coolest color scheme.
I am not getting involved
in this.
Although everyone knows
green is the best.
What was that?
Nothing.
Stay focused.
It's getting harder and harder
to find the trail
that Arin, and whoever
he's with, have left.
What if he's stuck alone
with Ras?
Ras is a master manipulator.
He could be brainwashing Arin,
and Arin would have no clue.
It's getting dark,
hard to see.
We'd better stop and make camp.
[grumbling]
[barking]
Did you know Arin's the one
who taught me
how to make a campfire?
Yeah.
In Imperium,
all our heating
was turned on by a switch.
[sighing heavily]
I didn't know I could miss
a person this much.
How does Zane deal with Pixal
being missing for so long?
Zane's a Nindroid.
Can he even have emotions?
[Lloyd laughing]
Ah, you have a lot to learn
about Zane, Frak.
He is much, much more
than a machine.
I hope he's okay.
We haven't heard from him
since we split up.
Maybe he's having
more success at finding Arin
than we are?
No significant signs of life--
organic or otherwise.
Let us move on
to the next valley.
[bird chirping]
[roaring in imitation]
[chirping and singing]
Do not dance with birds, Zanth.
I once did such things,
but have since learned
that behavior
is considered weird.
[groaning sadly]
[bird singing]
This area looks
as empty as the others.
Could that be
what I think it is?
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪♪
This is like
the other Monasteries
we have discovered.
Similar to ours,
yet strangely different.
[sniffing]
If my theory that each realm
gained its own Monastery
during the Merge
is true,
then this must be
this land's Monastery.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
A portal gate!
Exactly like
the other Monasteries.
[voices approaching]
Come on, Rapton!
This would be
a whole lot easier
if you'd just let us use a cart!
No way,
carts are Rapton's nemesis!
They know what they did.
Ah, besides, a little hard work
never hurt anybody.
Clearly, you've already
forgotten about Richard,
and statistically,
hard work
is the leading cause of--
It's about to become
the leading cause
of my boot in--
Um...
Excuse me, Rapton.
I do not believe those items
belong to you
or the Freebooters.
Oh, great, the ice cream ninja.
Uh, we have paperwork,
Mr. Ninja,
from a... dude.
The chain of ownership
is kinda murky, but--
Will you let Rapton
do the talking?
Just blast him!
Don't drop any of that stuff!
Please don't question
our professionalism.
We're very good looters.
Oh, so then
you don't need a cart!
Ugh!
Foiled by my own logic!
It cannot be!
[door crumbling]
No!
Excellent timing, Zanth!
Try to get me closer!
Almost...
[grunting with effort]
No life forms inside...
there!
Just what I was looking for!
[gasping]
[rock slamming]
Kreel would be jealous.
It is a literal junkyard
in here.
The Freebooters have been
more successful at looting
than I would have imagined,
but where...
A-ha!
If Kai and Nya could open
the Cocoon I was found in,
surely I can find a way
to open this one.
[mechanism powering on]
[hissing open]
Primary Interactive X-ternal
Assistant Life-Form now online.
Pixal!
Zane?
[sighing] Can't he ever come
at a normal hour?
Guess when you're him,
you show up whenever you want.
Just wish he'd stop
poking holes in my door.
A successful mission?
I never fail.
May I see it?
Money first.
Oh, of course.
Congratulations.
You just bought yourself
a rare Oni chalice
from the First Realm.
[hissing in delight]
I never dreamed
I'd get my hands
on such a thing.
Glorious!
Then our transaction
is complete.
Wait.
I was asked to pass
a message on to you.
Someone else
wants to contract your services.
Who is this from?
I don't know.
They were very secretive.
Asked you to meet them
at that location
in two days' time.
[Zane] I was beginning to fear
I would never see you again!
[Pixal]
I do not understand, Zane.
Why are you acting like this?
We just saw each other
this morning.
Though I am not sure
how I got in this weird place.
What is the last thing
you remember?
Some kind of strange storm.
Then everything went dark,
and now, you're
letting me out of this... thing.
Pixal,
it has been years
since we have seen each other.
The storm you remember
is something we now call
"the Merge,"
a mysterious event
that combined all the realms
into one,
apparently orchestrated
by Master Wu.
Master Wu?
Is he here as well?
It is very likely
he has departed.
Many strange things
have happened since the Merge.
I woke up
in a similar techno-cocoon
inside another Monastery
we found.
I will have to investigate
why that would happen
to us both.
There are other Monasteries?
There are also new Ninja!
[imitating Arin's voice]
Like Arin!
He's self-taught
in the art of Spinjitzu...
...and the art of making pies!
[imitating Sora's voice]
And Sora!
A master
at elemental tech abilities.
Not sure about her pie-making
abilities, however.
[in his own voice]
Then there's Riyu!
He is a small dragon
and doesn't talk like this.
He mostly makes sounds like--
[croaking and barking]
[snorting snarl]
[imitating Wyldfyre's voice]
Oh, and I can't forget Wyldfyre!
she would be upset
she wasn't mentioned first.
She's fiery,
but not Kai-fiery.
It was a thing.
I'm sad
to have missed all that.
[in his own voice]
I am sad you have as well.
During my most dire times
since the Merge,
when I was losing hope,
I would hear a voice in my head.
A voice that would center me,
giving me drive to continue,
even when the odds
were increasingly against us.
That voice, Pixal, was yours.
[Rapton] Aw...
Hate to break up
this tender moment...
Ha! Nah, Rapton loves
ruining tender moments!
That's an odd thing
to be in love with.
I was being
rhetorically dramatic!
You really should watch
more theater!
Hey, Ninja,
that robot is our loot,
and we hate losing our loot!
So either you voluntarily
cage yourselves,
or we're gonna have to turn
you both into scrap.
Shall we do what we do best?
I have missed you.
[grunting with effort]
Ah... h'yah!
Look out!
Ah!
R'ah!
[grunting with effort]
[blasting]
[gasping]
H'ah!
Incoming!
Understood.
[grunting with effort]
H'ah!
[grunting]
[grunting] Unh!
I love the other Ninja,
but you are the only one
who thinks the way I do, Pixal.
I am a bit surprised
to hear you so emotional.
It has been
a long time for me.
We have 'em!
How exactly do we have them?
Ah, well, we will have them
very shortly.
Appreciate the clarification.
We appear to be pinned down.
Appearances can be deceiving.
We simply need to leave,
in classic Ninja style.
[coughing]
Wh-What?
Is that a campfire?
[coughing]
There!
It's locked!
[Rapton] Get it open!
We need a safe spot to leap!
Somewhere we won't
get crushed against a rock.
That also.
Up ahead!
Get ready to jump!
One, two...
[thunderclaps]
Is that lightning?
This is very bad.
You know them?
I know the one in front.
And he'll probably tell us
something like--
[imitating Nokt's voice]
I will crush you to your doom.
Come, Dragonians!
Let us crush them
to their doom!
Sometimes,
I hate being so accurate.
Nokt is most likely
coming for me.
We must get off this train
and get as far away as possible.
On the count of three, we jump.
One--
[Nokt] We don't leave here
without the blade!
[Nokt]
No one onboard remains alive!
So Nokt is here
for some other reason.
I hate when
I am inaccurate as well.
He wants some sort of blade?
So we continue
doing what we do best.
[yelping]
[grunting with effort]
Who are these people now?
Can't anyone just loot
in peace anymore?
[blasting]
[growling]
It has to be here somewhere!
[gasping]
Finally.
H'yah!
What?
You!
I'd been hoping for a rematch
with the Ninja.
I have recently seen
another blade like this.
Its kind of power
should not be in your hands!
I don't care what you think.
[roaring]
[Nokt growling]
[grunting with effort]
[snarling]
[Freebooters shouting]
H'ah!
[blades clanking]
Um, are we on the same side?
-For now.
-Oh, thank goodness.
I couldn't handle
being kicked by more people.
H'ah!
[snarling]
[grunting with effort]
Give me that blade!
[roaring] Y'ah! H'ah!
[blasting]
H'ah!
[grunting with effort]
Bring me that sword!
[cackling]
After her!
Ah! Whoa!
[grunting with effort]
H'ah!
Unh! Ah!
Ah! Oh!
[gasping]
Yes!
No!
H'ah!
[snarling]
[grunting with effort]
Forget the ninja,
the weak point is the train.
[grunting with effort]
[train power surging]
[gasping]
It was nice to see you again.
Ah!
Zane!
The train is going faster!
We're going to crash!
Nokt is escaping,
and there is no way
to get the fallen Freebooters
safely off the train.
[Pixal]
And we are about to crash.
Don't forget the crash!
[Zane] I must find a way
to override the train controls!
[Pixal] Manually?
But the chances of success are--
[Zane] I am well aware
of my slim chances.
[Pixal] Of course you are.
Whoa!
[grunting with effort]
Ah!
This should work.
[grunting with effort]
I was presumptuous.
And we are out of time.
Zane! No!
[electricity crackling,
Zane groaning in pain]
[screaming]
[brakes screeching]
[screaming and groaning]
[brakes grinding]
[chuckling in triumph]
Rapton saves us yet again!
I was... not sure.
[groaning in pain]
[gasping]
Zane!
[electricity crackling]
Zane, no!
Listen to me!
It's Pixal, hear my voice!
[electricity crackling]
Zane!
Come back to me!
Pixal...
I thought I'd... lost you...
Never again.
[groaning in pain]
You're seriously damaged.
We need to get you help,
quickly.
We have...
other problems.
The Forbidden Five...
must be stopped.
[gasping]
[thunderclaps]
[snarling]
[screaming]
[shattering stone]
Hmm...
Exactly what we came for.
[evil laughter]
[♪♪♪]